saltandlavender.com 2018-12-23

# Privacy Policy, Disclosure, & Disclaimer • Salt & Lavender

Salt & Lavender found at https://www.saltandlavender.com/ (“Website”) is governed by the following Privacy Policy & Terms of Use.

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy & Terms of Use is to inform you what personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used. This statement only applies to this Website.

###  **WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT AND HOW IS IT USED?**

 **Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website** : We may collect personal information from you such as your name or email address. For example, you may voluntarily submit information to the Website by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form.

You may choose not to provide any Personal Information. If you have already provided it, you may [contact us](https://www.saltandlavender.com/contact/) if you prefer to have it removed. Be aware that this may limit your ability to use some of our products and features on the Website.

If you wish to opt out of email newsletters, you can do this on your own by using the unsubscribe link from the newsletter.

 **Automatically Collected Information** : We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access the Website. For example, when you use the Website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the Website, such as links clicked.

 **Cookies** : We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the Website.

The Website uses cookies to store visitors’ preferences, record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit, ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, customize Website content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

Users may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies, by the Website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of our Website may be entirely usable.

 **Comments:  **When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection. Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service (we use Akismet – see their privacy policy here: https://automattic.com/privacy/).

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year. If you leave a comment on this Website, certain information may be publicly visible. Your email address will never be available publicly.  At your option, you may also add a link to your website.

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

If you have left comments on this Website, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

 **HOW YOUR INFORMATION MAY BE USED**

We may use the information collected in the following ways:

  * To operate and maintain the Website;
  * To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each email promotion will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings;
  * To send you administrative communications, such as administrative emails, confirmation emails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;
  * To respond to your comments or inquiries;
  * To provide you with user support;
  * To track and measure advertising on the Website;
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity.

###  **THIRD-PARTY USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

The third-party service providers used by this website include:

 **Google Analytics** – this service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website.

This Website uses Google Analytics to collect traffic data. All websites which collect traffic data, which is more than 1/2 of all websites on the Internet, have the ability to monitor visitor information such as IP addresses, browser type, operating system, location, date/time of visit, and information about which areas of the site are visited. The data is anonymous and does not personally identify you. It is used solely for improving the user experience of our audience as a whole.

In compliance with the GDPR, our Google Analytics does not store your full IP address. Instead, the last octet of your IP is reset to zeros before any processing or storing takes place. This means that it cannot be used to identify you at all. If you want to opt out of Google Analytics, you can do so by following this guide: https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en

 **MailChimp** – this service is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications.  Please refer to MailChimp’s privacy policy (https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) for further information.

 **Social Warfare** – this service allows blog posts to be shared to social media. When a visitor clicks the share button, his or her social network login info is sent to the appropriate network to enable the share to happen. None of this is stored by Social Warfare – they tap into each social network’s API for sharing and allow the buttons to trigger that native sharing mechanism. Anonymous visit data may be collected via Google Analytics, such as what pages were visited, what browser the visitor used, etc. – this does not contain any personally identifiable information. Please see their privacy policy here for further information: https://warfareplugins.com/privacy-policy/.

 **Caching** – This Website uses cache technology to ensure that you can view this blog as fast as possible, so this necessitates the use of cookies. These save frequently used parts of our site to your device’s cache so it does not need to be drawn from the web server by ascertaining your general location to deliver our Website from a local server that’s closer to you.

 **Security** – This Website also uses plugins to help secure the website, which use cookies to identify IP addresses so we can protect this Website and ward off malicious attacks if necessary.

 _ **Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us.**_

 **ANONYMOUS DATA**

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

###  **ADVERTISING**

 **Display Ads**

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies, as noted above.

All advertising on this Website is in the form of advertisements generated by a third party ad network. This network may use aggregated, non-personally identifiable information about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please refer to http://www.networkadvertising.org. To opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit http://www.aboutads.info/choices.

AdSense allows third party vendors, including Google, to use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to this Website. Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads based on your visit to this and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the ads preference manager.

 **Retargeting  Ads**

From time to time, the Website may engage in remarketing efforts with third-party companies, such as Google, Facebook, or Instagram, in order to market the Website. These companies use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the Website.

 **Affiliate Program Participation**

The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

Salt & Lavender is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and links to Amazon.com.

As part of this Amazon Associates program, the Website will post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track the referrals to their website. This program utilizes cookies to track visits for the purposes of assigning commission on these sales.

Salt & Lavender may also use affiliate links from other companies such as [ShareASale.com](https://www.shareasale.com/) or [RewardStyle](https://www.rewardstyle.com/).

 **Newsletters**

On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user. This behavior will not be passed on to third parties.

###  **RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Opt-out – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at saltandlavender (at) gmail.com to be removed from our mailing list. In compliance with the GDPR, we will erase all data on our side upon request. For any data that resides on your computer, such as cookies or push notification opt-in, you would need to remove it yourself.

Access – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to saltandlavender (at) gmail.com

Amend – You may contact us at saltandlavender (at) gmail.com to amend or update your personal information.

Forget – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to saltandlavender (at) gmail.com

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

 **SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION**

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

 **CHILDREN’S INFORMATION**

The Website does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that the Website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at saltandlavender (at) gmail.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

 **CONTACT INFORMATION**

At any time, please contact us at saltandlavender (at) gmail.com for questions related to this Privacy Policy.

We retain the right to change or update this policy at any time.

###  **Embedded Content from Other Websites**

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

###  **No Warranty**

Salt & Lavender does not make any warranties of any kind.

The Website is provided on an “as is” and “as available” basis. Salt & Lavender disclaims all warranties, express and implied, including but not limited to fitness for a particular purpose, merchantability, non-infringement, availability, or security.

We make a reasonable effort to provide accurate information, but cannot warrant that any information provided is accurate, complete, reliable, or current. We provide no warranty or assume no liability for any information on the Website.

###  **Nutrition Disclaimer**

I am not a professional chef, dietician, medical professional, or nutritionist. This blog is a reflection of my opinions and general knowledge that I’ve gained from personal experience and information I’ve come across, and it’s accurate to the best of my knowledge. My recipes should be taken as a guideline only, and your best judgment should be used to ensure the food is safely prepared and/or a good fit for your diet. Please consult a medical professional if you are unsure.

Calorie information is provided on some of my recipes. This information is provided as a courtesy only and should be construed as an estimate rather than a guarantee. To calculate this information, I use online nutrition calculators and existing nutrition labels, which may have errors that I am unaware of. Ingredients themselves and products from brand-to-brand vary, so please use your best judgment (and/or consult a nutritionist) if relying on this nutritional information e.g. if you are following a specific diet.

###  **Content Policy**

Salt & Lavender Inc. owns the rights to the recipe photo content and recipes on this blog. All recipe photography on this site is our own unless otherwise indicated with a source link. Please do not republish any recipe or post without our permission. If you want to use one of our photos with a link back for a roundup style post, that’s fine. [Contact us](https://www.saltandlavender.com/contact/) if you have any questions.

###  **Sponsored Posts**

This Website will occasionally be compensated by brands or companies to feature their products in blog posts. This relationship will always be disclosed within the blog post. We only work with brands that we feel are a good fit for this blog and only promote products that we believe in.

Some sponsored posts may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in the post and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns.

###  **Links to Other Websites**

This Website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

###  **Content Submissions**

Content submitted by you to us in any form, including but not limited to submissions on the Website, email, and social media platforms, becomes the permanent property of Salt & Lavender, to be used as we see fit for any purpose, to the maximum extent of the law. You represent that you own the right to these submissions and are not breaking any laws by doing so. You agree to comply with all intellectual property laws, including but not limited to copyright and trademark laws, and to be solely responsible for any violations of laws for any content that you submit to us. You agree not to submit content that is defamatory, obscene, pornographic, abusive, threatening, soliciting in nature, or in violation of any law. By submitting content to us, you grant us a license to use it in any way, including without limitation, a right to copy, distribute, transmit, publicly display, reproduce, edit, translate and reformat it.

###  **Indemnity**

You agree to indemnify, defend, and hold harmless Salt & Lavender from any and all third party claims, losses, liability, damages, and/or costs, including reasonable attorney fees and costs, arising from your access to or use of the Website or your violation of these Terms of Use. We will notify you promptly of any such claim, loss, liability, or demand, and will provide you with reasonable assistance, at your expense, in defending any such claim, loss, liability, damage, or cost.

 _Updated May 24, 2018._
